Shivansh Kuchchal

Senior Software Engineer

shivanshbox@gmail.com

github.com/shivanshkc

in linkedin.com/in/shivanshk



₽ Profile

Software Engineer with 6 years of experience in application development using Go and Node.js. Experienced as lead developer, managed a team of 3 people to deliver a blockchain-based solution along with detailed technical documentation. Excellent learner and passionate about distributed systems.



Professional Experience

Senior Software Engineer, Red Hat Inc. □

2021 - present | Pune, India

- Single-handedly designed Red Hat's AWS marketplace integration system using Go and PostgreSQL.
- Leveraged the AWS Catalog API to automate the creation of private offers for Red Hat customers.
- Implemented jobs and state transitions to keep local state in sync with the AWS state.
- Implemented performant REST APIs with RBAC to read and write the state of private offers.
- Researched and executed leader election in a data synchronization service using Apache Zookeeper.

Software Engineer, KNNX Corp. □

2019 - 2021 | Hyderabad, India

- Created a powerful business Rules Engine service, based on the Hyperledger Fabric Blockchain.
- Introduced multi-tenancy in the system by adding abstractions such as Tenants and Applications.
- Integrated with KNNX Corp SSO system for seamless authorization.
- Implemented REST APIs on Applications, Rules and Functions using Node.js and CouchDB.
- Worked with the vm2 package in Node.js for safe rule evaulation.
- Implemented an extensible WebSocket event handler in Node.js for lightning fast rule evaluation.



Skills

Programming Languages

Go, TLA+, Javascript, Typescript, Python

APIs and Connectivity

REST APIs, Websocket, gRPC and Protocol Buffers

Databases

MongoDB, CouchDB, Redis, PostgreSQL, Elasticsearch, AWS S3

Distributed Systems

Apache Kafka, Apache Zookeeper, Hyperledger Fabric Blockchain, NGINX, GCP Cloud Run

Projects

Kevlar, A Novel Distributed Consensus Algorithm

2019 - present

- Researched extensively on distributed systems to create a new consensus algorithm.
- Wrote a complete **TLA+ specification** to guarantee algorithm safety.
- Developed a strong understanding of Paxos and Raft consensus algorithms.

Rosenbridge, A Distributed Communication Hub

2021 - present

- Rosenbridge is a distributed websocket hub for fast communication between machines.
- Connect using the CLI client github.com/shivanshkc/rosenbridge-cli
- Source code at github.com/shivanshkc/rosenbridge ☑

Authorizer, A Clean Implementation of OAuth in Go

2022 - present

- Developed a secure, extensible OAuth 2.0 service in Go supporting the full Google authentication flow.
- Implemented robust security including **PKCE**, **CSRF** protection, and HTTP-only cookie-based sessions.
- Engineered the service for production with multi-stage Docker builds and efficient CI/CD pipelines.

International Tech Talks

DevConf 2024 Brno, Czech Republic

- Delivered a workshop titled "Building Leader Election with Zookeeper, Go and Docker".
- The workshop lasted for 60 minutes, followed by a 20-minute Q&A session.
- Presentation link: Building Leader Election with Zookeeper, Go and Docker

NadoCon' 2023 Brno, Czech Republic

- The subject of my tech talk was "Distributed Systems and the CAP Theorem".
- The talk attracted a diverse physical audience, including attendees from the US, Europe, and Brazil.
- For further reference, here is the presentation link: Distributed Systems and CAP Theorem 🛭 .

Education

Bachelor of Technology, KIET Group of Institutions

2015 - 2019 | Ghaziabad, India

KIET Group of Institutions is a renowned college under Dr APJ Abdul Kalam Technical University 2. Although my degree in Mechanical Engineering may seem unrelated to Computer Science, the course included comprehensive Engineering Mathematics, sparking my initial interest in programming.